Alchemy, the science of understanding,
deconstructing, and reconstructing matter.
However, it is not an all-powerful art.
It is impossible to create
something out of nothing.
If one wishes to obtain something,
something of equal value must be given.
This is the law of equivalent exchange,
the basis of all alchemy.
In accordance with this law,
there is a taboo among alchemists.
Human transmutation is strictly forbidden.
For what could equal the value
of a human soul?
Kono omoi wo keshite shimau niwa
mada jinsei nagai dsho?
Yarinokoshite'ru koto
yarinaoshite mitai kara
Yume no tsuzuki oikakete ita hazu na no ni
Magarikunetta
hosoi michi hito ni tsumazuku
Ano koro mitai ni tte modoritai wake ja nai ni
Nakushite kita sora wo sagashite'ru
Wakatte kuremasu you ni
Gisei ni natta you na
kanashii kao wa yamete yo
Tsumi no saigo wa namida ja nai yo
Zutto kurushiku seotte'ku n da
Deguchi mienai kanjou meiro ni
dare wo matte'ru no?
Shiroi nooto ni tsuzutta you ni
motto sunao ni hakidashitai yo
Nani kar nogaretai n da
genjitsu tte yatsu?
Kanaeru tame ni ikite'ru n datte
Sakebitaku naru yo Kikoete imasu ka?
Bunai n nante yatte'rarenai kara
...kaeru basho mo nai no
Yasashisa niwa itsumo kansha shite'ru
Dakara tsuyoku naritai
(I'm on the way)
Natsukashiku naru
konna itami mo kangei jan
God's children, who live upon this land,
pray in faith and ye shall be saved.
Those who have lost their way,
the Sun God Leto shall shine...
So what are you guys,
like street performers or something?
Seriously?! Do we look like
street performers to you?
Yeah, that's why I asked!
Let's go, Al.
RADIO: ...I am an Emmisary of the Sun God Leto...
Hey! Easy!
I didn't mean nothing by it.
Sorry, accident. We'll fix it!
How's that? It's smashed to hell!
Watch and learn, gramps.
Okay, here goes!
[TWINKLING]
There, see. How's that?
Amazing, it's a miracle! You've been touched
by the Sun God just like Father Cornello!
Touched by who now?
It's not a miracle, it's alchemy!
Oh, so you two are alchemists.
Right, I've heard of them!
Then maybe you've heard of us!
We're the Elric Brothers.
The Elric Brothers, you say?
Right...I do know that name!
The Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric, is that right?
[ED CHUCKLING]
Wow, so you're the young prodigy
they tell all the stories about?
You've grown so much!
Look at the armor!
That must be how he got
the name Fullmetal!
Uh...no! Um...
It's not me!
ENTIRE CROWD:
...Huh?
What? You mean it's
the little guy there?
Who's little?! Come here
and say that to my face I dare ya!
...Lift thy voice to God...
ED: So, what's with this guy on the radio?
T-That's our leader, Father Cornello.
We were lost until he came to town and
began teaching us all the ways of the Sun God Leto...
He grants eternal life to the souls of the faithful...
He can even resurrect the dead...
His miracles are proof that
what he says is true!
So this guy's claiming he
can bring the dead back to life?
Now that's something I gotta see.
[CROWD CHEERING]
Praise Leto!
ED: So that's it, huh?
What do you think?
There's nothing to  think!
That's alchemy, no doubt about it.
ED: But somehow he's ignoring the
law of equivalent exchange.
He should've only been able to transmute
that flower into an object of equal mass.
AL: And he's changing organic matter
into inorganic matter.
He shouldn't be able to do that...
Unless...
ED: Yeah, there's just one way...
Bingo!
[CHURCH BELLS RINGING]
O merciful God, please hear me.
Hear my prayer, I beg of you.
Please bring him back—
Huh, so this is the almighty Leto?
Welcome! Are you interested
in Letoism?
Nope, can't say I am.
Not really the religious type.
Well, I'm sorry to hear that.
To know God is to know hope.
If we believe in divine grace...
Then through Him, all things are possible.
If you believed...
I'm sure Leto would bless you
and make you grow taller!
Translation: "Sincere"
I'm sure Leto would bless you
and make you grow taller!
What's that supposed to mean?!
Translation: "Sincere"
Easy, brother,
she's just trying to help!
Translation: "Sincere"
[SIGHS] What about bringing
the dead back to life?
Do you believe that's possible, too?
Yes.
[SIGHS]
Water, 35 liters; carbon, 20 kilograms;
ammonia, 4 liters; lime, 1 .5 kilograms;
phosphorus, 800 grams; salt, 250 grams;
saltpeter, 100 grams, and various other trace elements.
Huh?
That list represents the complete chemical makeup
of the human body for the average adult.
It's been calculated to
the last microgram, but still,
There's never been one reported case
of successfully creating a human life.
And you're telling me something modern science
can't do, you can do with prayer?!
Lift thy voice to God!
And the prayers of the faithful
shall be answered!
Did I mention?
All those ingredients I read off...
Down at the market a kid could buy every
one of them for the spare change in his pocket.
As it turns out,
humans are pretty cheap.
No, that's blasphemy!
People are...
We are all children of God!
Created in His image!
[ED CHUCKLES]
You have to understand,
alchemists are scientists.
We don't believe in unprovable concepts
like creators or gods.
We observe the physical laws
that govern this world...
To try to learn the truth.
It's ironic, really.
That through the application of science,
we have in many ways been given the power to...
[CHUCKLES]
...play gods ourselves.
So you're putting yourself on the same
level as God?! That's just...sheer arrogance!
You know, there's an old myth...
About a hero who
flew on wings made of wax.
He thought he could touch the sun,
but when he got too close...
His wings melted and he came
crashing back down to Earth.
Right, Al?
AL: Brother...
I'm sorry, Miss,
this is difficult for me to ask,
But do you think your Father Cornello could
even save an arrogant scientist, like me?
Of course, that's wonderful!
If anyone can lead you
to the Creator's light, he can!
Father Cornello, there are visitors here
who wish to see you.
A child, and a man
wearing a suit of armor.
They would only give their names
as "the Elric Brothers".
I can't be bothered right now,
just send them away.
Wait! The Elrics? You're sure that's
what they said? You're positive?
Yes, Father, that's what they
called themselves. No mistake.
Damn!
Then this is a problem.
Edward Elric, the Fullmetal Alchemist,
has come to call on us.
That's him?!
The man in the armor?
Mmm. Dressing the part,
it would seem.
But why would a State Alchemist
be here in Liore?
Surely they can't have
found out about our plans?
It's possible this dog's nose
is too sharp for his own good.
This way, please.
Father Cornello is a busy man,
as you can imagine.
But you're in luck,
he's decided to spare a moment for you.
Yeah, thanks! We understand,
we won't take too much of his time.
Good, then it's agreed.
We'll make this quick.
Brother Cray, what is this?
What do you think you're doing?!
Rose, these heathens have come to ensnare
and discredit the Father. They're evil.
This is God's will.
Brother Cray...!
Well, like you said,
let's make this quick!
[GASPS]
Oh yeah, strike!
What's this commotion?
Ah, the Fullmetal Alchemist. Welcome
to the home of our sacred order.
Father Cornello!
CORNELLO: I must apologise
for my disciples' behavior.
It would seem they've
been misguided.
ED: Okay, let's say I believe you weren't
the one guiding them. What next?
Have you come to learn
the ways of Leto?
Well there are a few things
I'm curious about.
Like how you've been using
second-rate alchemy to deceive your followers.
[GASP]
My dear boy,
I don't know what you mean.
What your doubting eyes see as alchemy
are the miracles of the Sun God Leto.
Look again. Could mere alchemy create
something from nothing in this way?
ED: Yeah, that's
what I didn't get at first.
How can you perform transmutations
that ignore the law of equivalent exchange?
As I said,
because it isn't alchemy!
But then I started thinking about it...
If you'd somehow managed to acquire
a certain object to amplify your alchemy...
One that's said to
make the impossible possible...
That would explain everything.
What?!
I'm talking about
the Philosopher's Stone.
Your ring, that's it,
isn't it?
I've been looking for that.
The ring is just a ring.
I am God's humble servant,
it is from he alone that I derive my power.
Still trying to sell that line, huh?
If that's the way you wanna play it, I guess I'll have
to come up there and beat some truth out of ya.
My, you really are quite
the incorrigible heathen, aren't you?
Rose, dear?
Yes, Father?
That gun there beside you,
pick it up.
Uh...O-okay?
Now, child, I want you to shoot
the Fullmetal Alchemist.
[GASPS]
No, I...
Father I can't do that!
I am the Sun God's chosen emissary.
My word is the word of Leto himself.
Shoot him, Rose.
It's God's will.
[SHAKY BREATHING]
Why hesitate?
When you lost your fiance
to that tragic accident last year,
who was it that saved you
from the very depths of despair?
Have you forgotten?
[VOICE TREMBLING]
It was you, Father.
That's right. It was I who took your
hand and lead you into God's light.
And do you recall what it was
I promised you then?
You said if I had faith
you'd bring him back to life!
No, wait!
It's not me, honest!
[GASP]
Dammit,
I'm the Fullmetal Alchemist!
It's not him!
It's me!
It's the short one?!
You're kidding!
I'm sorry, but I...
I have to do this...
I don't have any choice.
ED: He's been lying to you, Rose.
You're wrong!
I've seen his miracles!
Father Cornello will bring
him back to life, I have faith!
Fine, then shoot.
Al!
[SHRIEKS]
Good. God Leto is pleased,
you have done well, my child.
Now pick up the gun and
shoot the other as well.
Haven't you made her do
enough already?
[GASPS]
But...your head...!
I thought you were...
Don't worry about it,
he's pretty solid.
Yeah, see?
No harm done.
An empty suit of armor that
walks and speaks!
Do you still doubt it, Rose?
This unholy thing is an abomination!
Evil of this kind must be purged!
[GROWLING]
And I believe my Chimera
should be up to the task.
So this is the sorta thing you do with
a Philosopher's Stone? That's just twisted.
[GASP]
Anyway, looks like I'll need a weapon.
No transmutation circle?!
So the State Alchemist title
isn't just for show, you truly are gifted.
However...!
[CHIMERA ROARS]
Your little spear is no match for
Chimera claws that tear through iron!
You shredded my pants.
But I guess those claws don't do
so good against steel!
Bite him, you stupid beast!
You like that, kitty?
Go on, get a good taste!
Your arm...
A brother trapped in armor...
I see. It's all
becoming clear now.
You did it, didn't you?
The one thing even the most novice
alchemist knows is strictly forbidden!
Why don't you come down
here and try me?
I'll show you real quick
who the novice is!
Fullmetal Alchemist.
Why don't you come down
here and try me?
I'll show you real quick
who the novice is!
Rose...
this is the price of their sin.
These fools attempted
human transmutation,
the greatest taboo
for any alchemist!
In their arrogance, they tried to
bring someone dead back to life.
He thought he could touch the sun, but when he got too close
his wings melted and he came crashing back down to Earth.
Oh, no...
This is what happens when you try to
play God, or whatever you wanna call it.
Take a good look, Rose.
Is this what you want?
So this is the great Fullmetal Alchemist,
Edward Elric, not even half a man.
Hell, not even half a boy!
And what are you?!
You're just a phony that can't do
anything without a Philosopher's Stone!
Father, we just want you to hand
over the Stone before you get hurt.
Don't be absurd!
Why? So you could use it
for yourself? Please.
If you fools are really so eager to play God,
then perhaps I should send you to meet him instead!
Huh?
Nah, me and God,
we don't get along too well.
Even if I went, he'd probably
just send me right back here.
[ROSE SCREAMS]
This way!
Well don't just stand there!
After them!
These heathens seek to harm the order!
They must be stopped!
That's far enough.
What are you gonna do, boy?
You're unarmed and outnumbered.
Look, just come quietly.
We don't wanna have to rough you up.
Ha ha ha ha!
Huh?!
[ALL SCREAMING]
Don't go easy just 'cause
he's a kid, you got that?
[YELLING]
[ED CACKLING]
AL: What do you think of
Cornello now, Rose?
He just opened fire, he didn't
care that you were in the way.
But...that's because...
What he said back there
is true, isn't it?
We're not evil. All we wanted was
to see our mom smile again.
But our transmutation failed.
What we made...
wasn't even human.
We learned our
mistake the hard way.
People don't come back
from the dead. Not ever.
That's not true!
I mean...
Alchemy is based on
the law of equivalent exchange.
The price of even a failed
human transmutation was enormous.
It cost my brother his left leg,
and it cost me my whole body.
Do you see it?
My brother drew that with his own blood.
[GASP]
His leg had been taken, he was bleeding,
I can't imagine the pain he was in...
But through all that he still gave up his
right arm to transmute my soul...
and bonded me
to this suit of armor.
Now, I just want to help him get his
body back to the way it was.
He wants to find a way to get
me back to normal, too.
It won't be easy.
We might even get killed along the way.
But that's the path we chose.
All we can do is keep moving.
But, Father Cornello said...
[GASP]
He said he could do it,
he promised me!
Just because you and your brother
failed that doesn't mean...
It doesn't mean he will!
There you are,
you infernal brat!
Look, can we just cut
the crap and talk here?
All I want are some straight
answers about the Stone.
Tell me what I need to know,
and I'll be on my way.
Or we could get the
military involved...?
Ask your questions.
You could do anything with a
Philosopher's Stone, right?
So why waste all that power
performing phony miracles?
Because with each miracle I can attract
new believers to the order.
Believers who would
lay down their lives for my sake!
I'm slowly building an army...
A legion of holy warriors,
unafraid to die!
In a few more years, I'll be ready to unleash
this mindless horde upon the world!
And I'll use the Philosopher's Stone
to tear this country apart.
Who knows?
I might even carve out a slice for you.
[CACKLING]
[ED JOINS LAUGHING]
CORNELLO: Wait, what are you  laughing about?
I knew it! You really
are a novice, aren't you?
[GASPS]
You don't mean that—?!
There were never
any miracles, Rose.
He lied to you.
He lied to everyone.
CORNELLO: Why, you...!
How long?!
How long has that been on?!
ED: From the start!
Your believers heard every word.
CORNELLO: How could you?!
You'll pay dearly for this!
Sorry, not today!
Just face it,
you're outclassed here.
I am without rival!
I-It's a rebound!
No! I won't be disgraced like this!
Now boy... behold...
[VOICE DISTORTING]
...the chosen emissary of the Sun God Leto!
My word is the divine word of God himself!
My fist is the almighty fist of judgement!
Oh yeah?
Fist of God, huh?
Well if that's what you want,
you can have it!
[GROANING]
Shut up!
Just give me the
Philosopher's Stone!
What the hell...?
The Stone...
It's supposed to be perfect material...
How did it just break like that?!
I-I don't know.
I don't know anything about it!
S-Spare me! Please! I-I was wrong!
Please, I beg you!
It's a damn fake.
Please, don't! I'm helpless without
the Stone. Spare me, please!
You mean we
went through all this...
Risked our lives for this
one possible chance...
and it's a fake?!
So u-uh...
what about me?
I don't care what you do,
just get outta here!
Right!
AL: And what about the Stone?
ED: Phony, just like him.
AL: Oh.
I'm sorry, Al. For awhile there I thought
we'd really found a way to get your body back.
ROSE: Give me the Philosopher's Stone!
AL: Rose...
Like I was just saying, it was a fake.
It wasn't real.
Besides, it's shattered now.
Liar! You wanna keep it for
yourself, don't you?!
So you can use it on your bodies!
That's right!
And so you can try to bring
your mother back again!
You shut up!
People don't come back from
the dead, Rose. Not ever.
Not ever.
But he promised me...
He said if I prayed it
would happen...
[CRYING]
...a miracle...
That hope was all I had left,
what am I supposed to believe in now?!
Tell me what to do!
Please!
I can't tell you that,
you have to figure it out.
Stand up and walk.
Keep moving forward.
You've got two good legs,
so use them.
You're strong enough to
make your own path.
Bring him out here!
We're through listening to those lies!
Show yourself! Just get out here!
Open up!
That damn brat, it's all all ruined!
Everything I worked for!
Yes, all that hard work for nothing.
Huh?!
I knew we should've just
incited a little rebellion.
You...!
I'm hungry, Lust, can I eat the old man?
Please, he's big and fat!
Not this one, Gluttony.
We don't want you giving yourself indigestion.
Now you too?
Everyone has mocked me!
I won't stand for—
I'd say this concludes
our business.
Just as things were beginning
to look promising, too.
Now I suppose we'll have to
start over from scratch.
Father won't be pleased.
In any case, it's time we started
thinking about our next move.
[CRUNCH]
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee kimi wa oboete imasu ka
Yakusoku chigiri shoka
no kaze ga tsutsumu
futari yorisotta
Muri na egao no ura
nobita kage o kakumau
Dakara kizukanu furi saisei o erabu
Table no ue no furuenai shirase machitsuzukete
kuuhaku no yoru o kuru hazu no nai asa mo
zenbu wakatte'tan da
Ano hi mita sora akaneiro no sora o
nee itsuka omoidasu deshou
Hatasenakatta yakusoku o idaite
futari arukidasu
Following the incident in Liore, Ed and Al travel to
the Eastern Command Center to report to Colonel Mustang.
Once there, they are taken to the home
of the Sewing Life Alchemist, Shou Tucker,
and his young daughter, Nina, where they hope
to learn more about the field of bio-alchemy.
Next time on Fullmetal Alchemist: Brotherhood
Episode 4: An Alchemist's Anguish
Some meetings in this life
are destined only for heartbreak.